Will Jenkins (Murray Leinster) Papers
Will Jenkins (Murray Leinster) Papers
- Writings
  - Fighting Horse Valley, Triple X Western, 1934; also published by Alfred King, Inc. (1934) (Box 21)
  - Fighting Horse Valley, additional material (Box 22)
  - Final addition, True Experience, 1924[?] (Box 22)
  - The fine art of forgiving, Telling Tales, 1922 (Box 22)
  - Fingerprints, Argosy, 1918 (Box 22)
  - The fireplace, Today's Woman, 1947 (Box 22)
  - First contact, 1945; typescript for Astounding (Box 22)
  - First contact, television script; includes correspondence (Box 22)
  - First date, American Magazine, 1942 (Box 22)
  - First mate of the Bulgora (Box 22)
  - The first sweetheart, Smart Set, 1917 (Box 22)
  - $500 reward, Action Stories, 1921 (Box 22)
  - Five star matinee, NBC, 1956-1957; radio program, mimeographed copy (Box 22)
  - Flamingo, Standard Magazine (Box 22)
  - The flat in the Bronx, Young's, 1918 (Box 22)
  - The flitmore, Country Gentleman, 1935 (Box 22)
  - Fly for your life [alternate title: Test pilot], American Magazine, 1940 (Box 22)
  - A flyer in old masters [alternate title: The clever crook], Complete Detective Novels, 1929 (Box 22)
  - Flying fish milk, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 22)
  - Fog [alternate title: 1804], Short Stories, 1924; 1940 (Box 22)
  - Football at forty below, Top Notch (Box 22)
  - Footprints, McLean's (Box 22)
  - Footprints in the snow, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1918 (Box 22)
  - For services rendered [alternate title: Blizzard], Argosy, 1945 (Box 22)
  - The forbidden planet, Dell's Fan Magazine (Box 22)
  - The forgotten planet, Gnome Press, 1954 (Box 23)
  - The forgotten planet, Ace, 1956 (Box 23)
  - Four from planet five, Gold Medal, 1958; 1964; book; includes correspondence; galleys (Box 23)
  - Four little ships, Astounding Stories, 1942 (Box 23)
  - Fourth dimensional demonstrator, Astounding Stories, 1935; also published in Sidewise in Time (1950) and Twist in Time (1960) (Box 23)
  - The Frankenstein twins, Black Mask, 1922 (Box 23)
  - A friend of Capt. Dick, Short Stories, 1936 (Box 23)
  - The friend of General Morales, Blue Book, 1939 (Box 23)
  - The friendly atom [alternate title: I feel good about the atom bomb], 1945 (Box 23)
  - Friends [alternate title: $4700], Short Stories, 1940 (Box 23)
  - Friends, Startling Stories, 1947 (Box 23)
  - From beyond the stars, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1947-1948; includes correspondence (Box 23)
  - Front line, Argosy (Box 23)
  - Front man, Collier's, 1938 (Box 23)
  - Fugitive from space, Amazing Stories, 1953 (Box 23)
  - The funeral, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 23)
  - Fury from Lilliput, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1949 (Box 24)
  - The gadget had a ghost, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1952 (Box 24)
  - The gallery gods, Argosy, 1920 (Box 24)
  - The gamblin' kid, Triple X Western and Alfred King Inc., 1931; 1933; book; includes correspondence (Box 24)
  - The garden of illusion, Snappy Stories, 1920 (Box 24)
  - Gateway to elsewhere [alternate title: Journey to Barkt], Startling Stories, also published by Ace Books (Box 24)
  - The general was an honest man, Collier's, 1948 (Box 24)
  - The generosity of Sidi Joss Piang, Ace High, 1924 (Box 24)
  - Gentlemen pirates all, Ace High, 1922 (Box 24)
  - George was a noble guy, Collier's, 1943 (Box 24)
  - Gesetz des zufalls, Terra Extra Band 154, 1967; German translation of "Gateway to elsewhere" above (Box 25)
  - Getting married, Today, 1930 (Box 25)
  - The ghost of Eldred Boone, Saucy Stories, 1922; includes original play, story draft, printer's proofs (Box 25)
  - The ghost on the wire, Top Notch, 1922 (Box 25)
  - The ghost planet, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1948; novelette; holograph and typescript (Box 25)
  - The girl and the highjacker, Love Stories, 1924 (Box 25)
  - The girl from the five and ten [alternate title: Bik Lin], Esquire, 1944 (Box 25)
  - The girl from the skies, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 25)
  - The girl I love, Smart Set, 1917 (Box 25)
  - The girl nobody believed, Smart Set, 1917 (Box 25)
  - The girl who made men curse, Smart Set, 1925 (Box 25)
  - The girl who married a burglar, Cupid's Diary, 1923 (Box 25)
  - The girl who married well [alternate title: Two-thirty to quarter to five], Today's Woman, 1945 (Box 25)
  - The girl whom the pearls loved, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 25)
  - The girl with the secret charm [alternate title: Birthday party], Saturday Evening Post, 1953 (Box 25)
  - The god who carried a cane, Danger Trail, 1927 (Box 25)
  - Goin' crazy, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1930 (Box 25)
  - The goldfish co-respondent, Snappy Stories, 1921 (Box 25)
  - Gone native, Telling Tales, 1924 (Box 25)
  - Good neighbor, Sir (Box 25)
  - Gravity pulls upward, Top Notch, 1923 (Box 25)
  - The great Canal Street jewel robbery, Mystery, 1927 (Box 25)
  - The great catastrophe, Thrill Book, 1919 (Box 25)
  - The great joke of Lope de Gama, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 25)
  - The great-great-grandmother and the atomic bomb, McLean's (Box 25)
  - Great stories of science fiction [alternate title: Reader's guide to science fiction], Random House, 1950; anthology (Box 25)
  - Great stories of science fiction [alternate title: Reader's guide to science fiction], Random House, 1950; anthology (Box 26)
  - The great sinner, Movie Magazine (Box 26)
  - The greatest scoundrel unhung, Argosy, 1936 (Box 26)
  - The Greeks bring gifts, MacFadden-Bartell, 1964; book; 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Gregory circle, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1947 (Box 26)
  - Gresham of the skies, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 26)
  - Grist, Short Stories, 1924 (Box 26)
  - Grooves, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1918 (Box 26)
  - Guest appearance, CBS radio, 1949; 1952; scripts (Box 26)
  - The gunfighter, Argosy, 1938 (Box 27)
  - Guns for Achin, Everybody's, 1928 (Box 27)
  - Half-wolf, Standard Magazine (Box 27)
  - The hallway, Younger Set, 1923 (Box 27)
  - The Halstead Street kid, Sunset, radio version; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Ham flier, Short Stories (Box 27)
  - The hand of god, Short Stories, 1929 (Box 27)
  - He looked like Robert Taylor, Woman's Home Companion, 1939 (Box 27)
  - He was a hero, Top Notch, 1924 (Box 27)
  - Headline, Cosmopolitan, 1939 (Box 27)
  - The heart of Bhandra, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 27)
  - The heiress, Smart Set, 1915; poem (Box 27)
  - Hennessey, Flynn's Detective Fiction Weekly, 1921 (Box 27)
  - Hermit (Box 27)
  - The hero, Movie Magazine (Box 27)
  - Heroes, People's, 1922 (Box 27)
  - Hero's wife, Cosmopolitan, 1943 (Box 27)
  - The hidden love, Love Stories, 1923 (Box 27)
  - High destiny, Toronto Star-Journal (Box 27)
  - Hill of the padre's curse [alternate title: Curse of the golden hill], Triple X Western, 1924 (Box 27)
  - His place [alternate title: Steel man], Collier's, 1940 (Box 27)
  - Historical note, Astounding Stories, 1951 (Box 27)
  - Hit and run, McLean's, 1938 (Box 28)
  - The honesty of the Baron de Cittabola, Zest, 1926 (Box 28)
  - The Hollywood murders, Black Bat, 1933 (Box 28)
  - Honest crook, Adventure (Box 28)
  - Honesty, Argosy, 1917 (Box 28)
  - Honeymoon on Dleka, Future Stories, 1954 (Box 28)
  - The hour after supper, Argosy, 1918 (Box 28)
  - How often have I lied, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 28)
  - Howdy, Short Stories, 1922 (Box 28)
  - Hunters, Collier's, 1940 (Box 28)
  - I give my life [alternate title: Widow Hodza], American Magazine, 1940 (Box 28)
  - I have a grievance, article (Box 28)
  - I have been a god, Smart Set, 1916 (Box 28)
  - I like her, Smart Set, 1915 (Box 28)
  - I love Jim, Life Story, 1924 (Box 28)
  - I stick my neck out, Writer's Yearbook, article (Box 28)
  - I was a prisoner of the Japs, Life Story, 1942 (Box 28)
  - If I could only cry, True Experience, 1924? (Box 28)
  - If you was a Moklin, Galaxy, 1951 (Box 28)
  - I was Americanized, Secrets, 1924 (Box 28)
  - I'll wait for you [alternate title: Hi, joe], Saturday Evening Post, 1955 (Box 28)
  - I'll wait for you [alternate title: Hi, Joe], CBS, 1956; television script; includes correspondence (Box 28)
  - Illusion, Argosy, 1937 (Box 28)
  - I'm afraid of the dark, Secrets (Box 28)
  - I'm fed up, article (Box 28)
  - Imbalance, Fantasy Science Fiction, 1964 (Box 28)
  - The impenetrable virtue of Elsie, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 28)
  - The impossible romance, Secrets, 1924 (Box 28)
  - In account with destiny, Short Stories, 1923 (Box 28)
  - In cold blood, Argosy, 1917 (Box 28)
  - In defense of popularity (Box 28)
  - In the fog, Standard Magazine, 1942 (Box 28)
  - In the hall of blue tiles, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 29)
  - Incident on Calypso, Startling Stories, 1945 (Box 29)
  - The incredible invasion, Astounding Stories, 1936; also published as half of the Ace Double Other Side of Here (1955); 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Inside straight, Movie Magazine (Box 29)
  - Interference, Astounding Stories, 1945 (Box 29)
  - Invaders, Galaxy, 1962 (Box 29)
  - Invasion, Astounding Stories, 1931 (Box 29)
  - Invasion into space, Berkley Publications, 1964; book (Box 29)
  - Invasion into space, Berkley Publications, 1964; book; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Island honor [alternate title: Lords of creation], Short Stories, 1924 (Box 30)
  - The island that looked like paradise, Blue Book, 1941; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Isn't it odd, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 30)
  - It, Esquire (Box 30)
  - It's swell, True Experience, 1924? (Box 30)
  - It's very simple, Young's, 1919 (Box 30)
  - Izzy, Argosy, 1918 (Box 30)
  - Jezebel, Startling Stories, 1953 (Box 30)
  - Jiggy jass, Argosy, 1929 (Box 30)
  - Jimmy Thorne frames himself, Tower Mystery Magazine, 1935 (Box 30)
  - A job for a hero, Top Notch, 1926 (Box 30)
  - John Smith is born, Short Stories (Box 30)
  - Jose of Ticao, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 31)
  - The journey, Star Science Fiction Stories, 1956; includes correspondence (Box 31)
  - Juice hog battle, Top Notch (Box 31)
  - The juggler of Notre Dame (Box 31)
  - Ju-ju, Thrill Book, 1919; novelette (Box 31)
  - June Taylor articles, 1956-1957; article "June Taylor Dances" and interview (Box 31)
  - Jungle, Philadelphia Inquirer (Box 31)
  - Jungle stream, Danger Trail, 1927 (Box 31)
  - Just a kiss or so, Young's [MISSING Nov 2007], 1922 (Box 31)
  - Just one Arabian night, Follies, 1922 (Box 31)
  - Keen mind (Box 31)
  - Keyhole, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1951; 1965; includes correspondence (Box 31)
  - Khilit, Everybody's, 1929 (Box 31)
  - The kid, People's, 1922 (Box 31)
  - The kid, Liberty, 1926 (Box 31)
  - The kid comes back, All Western, 1933 (Box 31)
  - The kid dies again, Toronto Star Weekly, 1939; 2 folders (Box 32)
  - The kid deputy, Triple X Western, 1935; also published by Alfred King, Inc. (1935) (Box 32)
  - The kidder, Argosy, 1939 (Box 32)
  - The killer, Ranch Romances, 1925 (Box 32)
  - The killer (Box 32)
  - The killing, Western Romances, 1931 (Box 32)
  - Killing at Thunder Mountain, Mystery, 1928 (Box 32)
  - The king of Bukhanara, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 32)
  - The king of Halstead Street, Argosy, 1938 (Box 32)
  - King Solomon's mines, Movie Magazine (Box 32)
  - King's pirate, Adventure (Box 32)
  - The king's Ylith, Startling Stories, 1949 (Box 32)
  - Kleen mind (Box 32)
  - Knight on a bike [alternate title: Adventure], American Magazine, 1939 (Box 32)
  - Kuantan, Short Stories (Box 32)
  - Labor of love, Astounding Stories, 1956; article (Box 32)
  - A lady of indiscretion, Young's, 1922 (Box 32)
  - The lady and the seabird (Box 32)
  - Lady without a passport, Movie Magazine (Box 32)
  - Lady Luck's stepchild, West, 1927 (Box 32)
  - The lambayo, Telling Tales, 1924 (Box 32)
  - Last date [alternate title: Spring night], Today's Woman, 1945 (Box 33)
  - The last grubstaker, Popular Publications (Box 33)
  - Last of the big shots, Standard Magazine (Box 33)
  - The last spaceship, Terra Extra Band 131, in German (Box 33)
  - The law of the six gun, Smashing Western, 1930 (Box 33)
  - Laws of chance, Startling Stories, 1947; also published as a book, Fight for Life (Crestwood, 1950); 2 folders (Box 33)
  - The leader, Astounding Stories, 1960 (Box 33)
  - Learning life from literature [alternate title: Four moments], This Week, 1941 (Box 33)
  - The legend of the seven stars, Strange Stories, 1928 (Box 33)
  - Leo the magnificent, Ace High, 1921 (Box 33)
  - A lesson in love, True Confessions, 1926? (Box 33)
  - Letter home, Collier's, 1943 (Box 33)
  - Letter on the sidewalk (Box 33)
  - Letters of silence, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 33)
  - The life work of Professor Muntz, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1949 (Box 33)
  - Lifeboat, Country Gentleman, 1941 (Box 33)
  - Lie to me, Millicent, Smart Set, 1917 (Box 33)
  - Like dups, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1946 (Box 33)
  - Limpy's drops, Argosy, 1936 (Box 33)
  - The lion mane collar, Collier's, 1939 (Box 34)
  - Little cigarette, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 34)
  - The little fool, Story Book, 1920 (Box 34)
  - Little old Mrs. Holcomb, Liberty, 1925 (Box 34)
  - Little sister, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 34)
  - Little sister, Young's, 1920 (Box 34)
  - The little terror [alternate title: Oogledeboo], Saturday Evening Post, 1952 (Box 34)
  - The little tin angel and the kid, True Confessions, 1926 (Box 34)
  - A little violence, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 34)
  - Little white dog, True Experience, 1924? (Box 34)
  - The locust dance, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 34)
  - A logic named Joe, Astounding Stories, 1946; also published as Sidewise in Time (Shasta, 1950) (Box 34)
  - The lonely planet, Thrilling Wonder Stories and Monsters and Such, 1949; 1959 (Box 34)
  - The lonely sea, Adventure, 1942 (Box 34)
  - The lost niggerhead, Short Stories, 1934 (Box 34)
  - The lost race, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1949 (Box 34)
  - A lover in disguise, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 34)
  - Loyalty, Sign Magazine, 1956 (Box 34)
  - Lucky break, Collier's, 1936 (Box 34)
  - Lucky Tompkins comes back, Western Stories, 1921 (Box 34)
  - The lunatic railroad, Top Notch (Box 34)
  - Lunch with one's wife's first husband, Esquire, 1947 (Box 34)
  - Lynch law, Telling Tales, 1921 (Box 34)
  - M fella boy firu, Short Stories (Box 34)
  - Magic bathing suits, Young's, 1921 (Box 34)
  - The maharaja, Triple X Western, 1924 (Box 34)
  - Mail rocket, 1951; comic strip; includes correspondence (Box 34)
  - The maintop, Blue Book, 1936 (Box 35)
  - The make believe marriage, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 35)
  - Man at the top [alternate title: The day Mr. Patten was fired], Saturday Evening Post, 1961 (Box 35)
  - Man in the iron cap, Startling Stories, 1947; also published as book, The Brainstealers, Ace (1954) (Box 35)
  - The man with the soft hat, Mike Shayne Magazine, 1961 (Box 35)
  - The man who blew up the war, Blue Book, 1939 (Box 35)
  - The man who carried the skyline, Sea Stories, 1923 (Box 35)
  - The man who could put out the sun, Argosy, 1930; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - The man who didn't shoot, Danger Trail, 1926 (Box 35)
  - The man who feared [alternate title: No clues], Detective Fiction Weekly, 1930; also published as a book by Wright and Brown, circa 1930; includes correspondence; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - The man who lived alone [alternate title: Monsieur Duchet], Collier's, 1939 (Box 35)
  - The man who paid to be murdered, Saucy Stories, 1919 (Box 36)
  - The man who shook the earth, Argosy, 1933; 2 folders (Box 36)
  - The man who understood women, Love Stories, 1924 (Box 36)
  - The man who was fired, 1922 (Box 36)
  - The man who went black, Ace High, 1922 (Box 36)
  - The man who wouldn't squeal, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1929 (Box 36)
  - The man with the bad smell, Today's Woman (Box 36)
  - The man without a face [alternate title: Them], Today's Woman (Box 36)
  - Man wolves, incomplete (Box 36)
  - Manhunt, Philadelphia Inquirer, 1950 (Box 36)
  - Manhunt, Liberty, 1938 (Box 36)
  - The maniac murders, Black Bat, 1934 (Box 36)
  - The manless worlds, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1947; also published in The Last Spaceship, Fell, 1949 (Box 36)
  - Marianina, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 36)
  - The masked bride, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 36)
  - A matter of honor, Secrets, 1924 (Box 36)
  - Maxie, Short Stories, 1940 (Box 36)
  - Mboka, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 36)
  - Meditation on fish, Esquire (Box 36)
  - Memo for the kindergarten, article (Box 36)
  - Men into space, Berkley Publications, 1960; includes correspondence (Box 36)
  - Merritt takes a chance, Fighting Romances, 1925 (Box 37)
  - A message to the Countess [alternate title: Cafe Hrodny], Collier's, 1937 (Box 37)
  - Mexican trail, West, 1930; book; also published by Alfred King, Inc., 1933; includes correspondence; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - The middle of the week after next, Startling Stories, 1952 (Box 37)
  - Mike comes to lunch, Collier's, 1938 (Box 37)
  - Milhao, Life Story, 1943 (Box 37)
  - Miners in the sky, Avon, 1964-1965; book; includes correspondence; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Miners in the sky, Avon, 1964-1965; book; includes correspondence (Box 38)
  - The mistakes, Follies, 1922 (Box 38)
  - Mr. Jinks, Top Notch (Box 38)
  - Mr. Peterson's other self, This Week, 1942 (Box 38)
  - Mr. Wildbeck [alternate title: Mr. Stern's brother-in-law], Liberty, 1937-1942; includes correspondence (Box 38)
  - Mistress Molly, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 38)
  - The mole-pirate, Astounding Stories, 1934 (Box 38)
  - Monster from earth's end [alternate title: Boojer beast], Gold Medal, 1958 (Box 38)
  - Monster from earth's end [alternate title: Boojer beast], Gold Medal, 1958; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Monster vom Ende der Welt, Utopia Zukunfts Roman, Nr. 549, 1959; in German (Box 39)
  - The monsters, Weird Tales, 1929 (Box 39)
  - A monumental mistake in writing, Writers Monthly, 1955; includes correspondence (Box 39)
  - Moonrise, Movie Magazine (Box 39)
  - Morale, Astounding Stories, 1931 (Box 39)
  - The Morrison monument, Argosy, 1935 (Box 39)
  - The mountain blood of Jamie Blair, Love Stories, 1922 (Box 39)
  - Mousetrap, Astounding Stories, 1954 (Box 39)
  - The mousy man, Mike Shayne Magazine, 1961 (Box 39)
  - Murder at the first night, Black Bat, 1933 (Box 40)
  - Murder in the family, Teck Publishers, 1933-1934; includes correspondence; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Murder madness, Brewer and Warren, 1931; book; drafts, corrections, galley proofs; 2 folders (Box 41)
  - The murder of the U.S.A., Crown, 1946; book; draft with corrections, galleys, deleted pages; 3 folders (Box 41)
  - The mutant weapon, Astounding Stories, 1956; book (Box 41)
  - The mutant weapon, Ace Books, circa 1959; book; also published as part of Pirates of Zan; includes correspondence (Box 41)
  - My darling Clementine, McFadden Publishers, 1946; carbon, first draft with corrections (Box 41)
  - My darling Clementine, "fair copy" (Box 42)
  - My friend Raoul, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 42)
  - My husband's friend, Secrets, 1922 (Box 42)
  - My neighbor's wife, Smart Set, 1916 (Box 42)
  - My nephew Jaime (Box 42)
  - My son's wife, Secrets, 1924 (Box 42)
  - Mysterious stranger [alternate title: Grandma Norton's love life], Today's Woman, 1944 (Box 42)
  - The mystery of the kidnapped goldfish, Detective Story Magazine, 1922 (Box 42)
  - The mystery of the magnolias, Love Stories, 1921 (Box 42)
  - Mystery of the murdered waxwork, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1929 (Box 42)
  - Nameless something, Thrilling Wonder Stories, 1947 (Box 42)
  - Narrative needs a third dimension, article (Box 42)
  - The necklace in the bath-house, Black Bat, 1934 (Box 42)
  - Nemesis, Argosy, 1932 (Box 42)
  - Nerve, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1921 (Box 42)
  - The night and the city, Movie Magazine (Box 42)
  - The night before the end of the world, Famous fantasy, 1948 (Box 42)
  - Night drive, Today's Woman, 1949; includes correspondence (Box 42)
  - The night has a thousand eyes, Movie Magazine (Box 42)
  - A night of Mr. Waddy, McLean's, 1949 (Box 42)
  - Nightmare planet, Amazing Stories, 1961 (Box 42)
  - Nightmare planet, Science Fiction, 1953; part of book The Forgotten Planet (Box 42)
  - Nineteen, Standard Magazine (Box 43)
  - No difference at all, Today's Woman, 1944 (Box 43)
  - No highway, Movie Magazine (Box 43)
  - No man's reef, Young's, 1919 (Box 43)
  - No more trouble, Country Gentleman, 1939 (Box 43)
  - No more walls [alternate title: Con], Collier's, 1937 (Box 43)
  - No name no. 1, Love Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 2, Love Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 3, Love Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 4, Love Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 5, Secrets-Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 6, Secrets-Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 7, Secrets-Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 8, Secrets-Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 9, Secrets-Stories (Box 43)
  - No name no. 10, Secrets-Stories, 1922 (Box 43)
  - No road to high [alternate title: Stepfather], Saturday Evening Post, 1962 (Box 43)
  - Nobody saw the ship, Famous Science Fiction, 1950; also published in Monsters and Such (1959) (Box 43)
  - North of sixty-three, Detective Fiction Weekly, 1934 (Box 43)
  - Not quite a lady, This Week, 1938 (Box 43)
  - A novelty in ethics, Telling Tales, 1921 (Box 43)
  - The obtuse angle, Telling Tales, 1922 (Box 43)
  - Of destiny, American Magazine, 1949 (Box 43)
  - Offshore breeze, Argosy, 1922 (Box 43)
  - Oh, Aladdin, Argosy All-Story Weekly, 1918 (Box 43)
  - Ohuie, Telling Tales, 1936 (Box 43)
  - Old flame [alternate title: Man of war], Collier's, 1939 (Box 43)
  - The old man with the young wife, Saucy Stories, 1922 (Box 43)
  - Old married folks, Snappy Stories, 1918 (Box 44)
  - An old Persian customer, Argosy, 1939 (Box 44)
  - Old Pete, Dime Western, 1933 (Box 44)
  - The oldest story in the world, Ace High, 1922; 1937; includes correspondence (Box 44)
  - On the advantage of being honest, Saucy Stories, 1922 (Box 44)
  - On ivory towers, Writer's Yearbook (Box 44)
  - Once and for all [alternate title: The sheriff's son-in-law], Collier's, 1940 (Box 44)
  - One double-O-nine, Top Notch, 1923 (Box 44)
  - One-fella Memena's string, Short Stories (Box 44)
  - One fifteen p.m. (Box 44)
  - One husband's dog (Box 44)
  - One small smudge of soot, Live Stories and Star Magazine, 1921; 1931 (Box 44)
  - One traitor among us [alternate title: The inhabitants of San Giorgio], Life Story (Box 44)
  - The only honest Dick (Box 44)
  - Operation outer space, MacTalley and Fantasy Press, 1954 (Box 44)
  - [Operation outer space] Fernsehstudio Galaxis, Terra Extra Band 137, 1967; in German (Box 44)
  - Operation Pacific, Movie Magazine (Box 45)
  - Operation terror, Berkley Publications, 1962; 2 folders (Box 45)
  - The other now, Galaxy, 1960; also published in Twists in Time (Avon, 1946) (Box 45)
  - The other now, WJC and network, 1953; radio script (Box 45)
  - The other worlds, Startling Stories, 1949; serial (Box 45)
  - Outlaw, Standard Magazine and Giant Western, 1944; 1951 (Box 45)
  - An outlaw retires, Popular Publ. (Box 45)
  - Outlaw sheriff, Triple X Western, 1934; also published by Alfred King, Inc.; original with corrections, carbon copy; 2 folders (Box 46)
  - Outside the wall, Movie Magazine (Box 46)
  - Overdrive, Startling Stories, 1953 (Box 46)
  - The owner of the Aztec, West, 1926 (Box 46)
  - Padre Silvestre, Snappy Stories, 1919 (Box 46)
  - Panhandle, Movie Magazine (Box 46)
  - Panic, Toronto Star Weekly, 1939 (Box 46)
  - Panther's moon, Movie Magazine (Box 46)
  - Pao Ching Mien Yang, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 47)
  - Papa Bloom, Holland's Magazine (Box 47)
  - Pariah Planet, Amazing Stories, Ace Books, 1961; book; original with corrections, carbon copy; 2 folders (Box 47)
  - The party line in literature, article (Box 47)
  - Payday, Standard Magazine, 1943 (Box 47)
  - The payoff [alternate title: Motive], Cosmopolitan (Box 47)
  - Payung, Danger Trail, 1927? (Box 47)
  - The pearl, Movie Magazine (Box 47)
  - The pebble of justice, Argosy, 1939 (Box 47)
  - Pepita (Box 47)
  - The perfect explanation, Snappy Stories, 1917 (Box 47)